<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Geo Wiki</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="about">About App</string>
    <string name="title_activity_list1">List1</string>
    <string name="mercury_info">\n<b>Orbit:</b> 57,910,000 km (0.38 AU) from Sun \n
<b>Diameter:</b> 4,880 km \n
<b>Mass:</b> 3.30e23 kg</string>
    <string name="mercury">Mercury has been known since at least the time of the Sumerians (3rd millennium BC). It was sometimes given separate names for its apparitions as a morning star and as an evening star. Greek astronomers knew, however, that the two names referred to the same body. Heraclitus even believed that Mercury and Venus orbit the Sun, not the Earth.\n\n

Since it is closer to the Sun than the Earth, the illumination of Mercury\'s disk varies when viewed with a telescope from our perspective. Galileo\'s telescope was too small to see Mercury\'s phases but he did see the phases of Venus.\n\n
    Mercury\'s orbit is highly eccentric; at perihelion it is only 46 million km from the Sun but at aphelion it is 70 million. The position of the perihelion processes around the Sun at a very slow rate. 19th century astronomers made very careful observations of Mercury\'s orbital parameters but could not adequately explain them using Newtonian mechanics. The tiny differences between the observed and predicted values were a minor but nagging problem for many decades. It was thought that another planet (sometimes called Vulcan) slightly closer to the Sun than Mercury might account for the discrepancy. But despite much effort, no such planet was found. The real answer turned out to be much more dramatic: Einstein\'s General Theory of Relativity! Its correct prediction of the motions of Mercury was an important factor in the early acceptance of the theory.</string>

    <string name="venus_info">Orbit: 108,200,000 km (0.72 AU) from Sun\n
Diameter: 12,103.6 km\n
Mass: 4.869e24 kg</string>
    <string name="venus">Venus (Greek: Aphrodite; Babylonian: Ishtar) is the goddess of love and beauty. The planet is so named probably because it is the brightest of the planets known to the ancients. (With a few exceptions, the surface features on Venus are named for female figures.)\n\n
Venus has been known since prehistoric times. It is the brightest object in the sky except for the Sun and the Moon. Like Mercury, it was popularly thought to be two separate bodies: Eosphorus as the morning star and Hesperus as the evening star, but the Greek astronomers knew better. (Venus\'s apparition as the morning star is also sometimes called Lucifer.)
    \n\nVenus rotation is somewhat unusual in that it is both very slow (243 Earth days per Venus day, slightly longer than Venus year) and retrograde. In addition, the periods of Venus rotation and of its orbit are synchronized such that it always presents the same face toward Earth when the two planets are at their closest approach. Whether this is a resonance effect or merely a coincidence is not known.</string>
    <string name="earth_info">Orbit: 149,600,000 km (1.00 AU) from Sun\n
Diameter: 12,756.3 km\n
Mass: 5.972e24 kg</string>
    <string name="earth">Earth is the only planet whose English name does not derive from Greek/Roman mythology. The name derives from Old English and Germanic. There are, of course, hundreds of other names for the planet in other languages. In Roman Mythology, the goddess of the Earth was Tellus - the fertile soil (Greek: Gaia, terra mater - Mother Earth).\n\n

It was not until the time of Copernicus (the sixteenth century) that it was understood that the Earth is just another planet.\n\n

 Mir and Earth\'s limbEarth, of course, can be studied without the aid of spacecraft. Nevertheless it was not until the twentieth century that we had maps of the entire planet. Pictures of the planet taken from space are of considerable importance; for example, they are an enormous help in weather prediction and especially in tracking and predicting hurricanes. And they are extraordinarily beautiful.</string>

    <string name="mars_info">Orbit: 227,940,000 km (1.52 AU) from Sun\n
Diameter: 6,794 km\n
Mass: 6.4219e23 kg</string>
    <string name="mars">Mars (Greek: Ares) is the god of War. The planet probably got this name due to its red color; Mars is sometimes referred to as the Red Planet. (An interesting side note: the Roman god Mars was a god of agriculture before becoming associated with the Greek Ares; those in favor of colonizing and terraforming Mars may prefer this symbolism.) The name of the month March derives from Mars.\n\n

Mars has been known since prehistoric times. Of course, it has been extensively studied with ground-based observatories. But even very large telescopes find Mars a difficult target, it\'s just too small. It is still a favorite of science fiction writers as the most favorable place in the Solar System (other than Earth!) for human habitation. But the famous \"canals\" \"seen\" by Lowell and others were, unfortunately, just as imaginary as Barsoomian princesses.\n\n
    Mars orbit is significantly elliptical. One result of this is a temperature variation of about 30 C at the subsolar point between aphelion and perihelion. This has a major influence on Mars climate. While the average temperature on Mars is about 218 K (-55 C, -67 F), Martian surface temperatures range widely from as little as 140 K (-133 C, -207 F) at the winter pole to almost 300 K (27 C, 80 F) on the day side during summer.</string>
    <string name="jupiter_info">Orbit: 778,330,000 km (5.20 AU) from Sun \n
Diameter: 142,984 km (equatorial)\n
Mass: 1.900e27 kg</string>
    <string name="jupiter">Jupiter (a.k.a. Jove; Greek Zeus) was the King of the Gods, the ruler of Olympus and the patron of the Roman state. Zeus was the son of Cronus (Saturn).\n\n
Jupiter is the fourth brightest object in the sky (after the Sun, the Moon and Venus). It has been known since prehistoric times as a bright \"wandering star\". But in 1610 when Galileo first pointed a telescope at the sky he discovered Jupiter\'s four large moons Io, Europa, Ganymede and Callisto (now known as the Galilean moons) and recorded their motions back and forth around Jupiter. This was the first discovery of a center of motion not apparently centered on the Earth. It was a major point in favor of Copernicus\'s heliocentric theory of the motions of the planets (along with other new evidence from his telescope: the phases of Venus and the mountains on the Moon). Galileo\'s outspoken support of the Copernican theory got him in trouble with the Inquisition. Today anyone can repeat Galileo\'s observations (without fear of retribution :-) using binoculars or an inexpensive telescope.</string>
    <string name="saturn_info">Orbit: 1,429,400,000 km (9.54 AU) from Sun\n
Diameter: 120,536 km (equatorial)\n
Mass: 5.68e26 kg</string>
    <string name="saturn">In Roman mythology, Saturn is the god of agriculture. The associated Greek god, Cronus, was the son of Uranus and Gaia and the father of Zeus (Jupiter). Saturn is the root of the English word \"Saturday\" .\n\n
Saturn has been known since prehistoric times. Galileo was the first to observe it with a telescope in 1610; he noted its odd appearance but was confused by it. Early observations of Saturn were complicated by the fact that the Earth passes through the plane of Saturn\'s rings every few years as Saturn moves in its orbit. A low resolution image of Saturn therefore changes drastically. It was not until 1659 that Christiaan Huygens correctly inferred the geometry of the rings. Saturn\'s rings remained unique in the known solar system until 1977 when very faint rings were discovered around Uranus (and shortly thereafter around Jupiter and Neptune).\n\n
    Saturn is visibly flattened (oblate) when viewed through a small telescope; its equatorial and polar diameters vary by almost 10% (120,536 km vs. 108,728 km). This is the result of its rapid rotation and fluid state. The other gas planets are also oblate, but not so much so.</string>
    <string name="uranus_info">Orbit: 2,870,990,000 km (19.218 AU) from Sun\n
Diameter: 51,118 km (equatorial)\n
Mass: 8.683e25 kg</string>
    <string name="uranus">Uranus is the ancient Greek deity of the Heavens, the earliest supreme god. Uranus was the son and mate of Gaia the father of Cronus (Saturn) and of the Cyclopes and Titans (predecessors of the Olympian gods).\n\n

Uranus, the first planet discovered in modern times, was discovered by William Herschel while systematically searching the sky with his telescope on March 13, 1781. It had actually been seen many times before but ignored as simply another star (the earliest recorded sighting was in 1690 when John Flamsteed cataloged it as 34 Tauri). Herschel named it \"the Georgium Sidus\" (the Georgian Planet) in honor of his patron, the infamous (to Americans) King George III of England; others called it \"Herschel\". The name \"Uranus\" was first proposed by Bode in conformity with the other planetary names from classical mythology but didn\'t come into common use until 1850</string>
    <string name="pluto_info">Orbit: 5,913,520,000 km (39.5 AU) from the Sun (average)\n
Diameter: 2372 km\n
Mass: 1.303e22 kg</string>
    <string name="pluto">In Roman mythology, Pluto (Greek: Hades) is the god of the underworld. The planet received this name (after many other suggestions) perhaps because it\'s so far from the Sun that it is in perpetual darkness and perhaps because \"PL\" are the initials of Percival Lowell.\n\n

 Pluto was discovered in 1930 by a fortunate accident. Calculations which later turned out to be in error had predicted a planet beyond Neptune, based on the motions of Uranus and Neptune. Not knowing of the error, Clyde W. Tombaugh at Lowell Observatory in Arizona did a very careful sky survey which turned up Pluto anyway.\n\n

After the discovery of Pluto, it was quickly determined that Pluto was too small to account for the discrepancies in the orbits of the other planets. The search for Planet X continued but nothing was found. Nor is it likely that it ever will be: the discrepancies vanish if the mass of Neptune determined from the Voyager 2 encounter with Neptune is used. There is no Planet X. But that doesn\'t mean there aren\'t other objects out there, only that there isn\'t a relatively large and close one like Planet X was assumed to be. In fact, we now know that there are a very large number of small objects in the Kuiper Belt beyond the orbit of Neptune, some roughly the same size as Pluto.</string>
    <string name="neptune_info">Orbit: 4,504,000,000 km (30.06 AU) from Sun\n
Diameter: 49,532 km (equatorial)\n
Mass: 1.0247e26 kg</string>
    <string name="neptune">After the discovery of Uranus, it was noticed that its orbit was not as it should be in accordance with Newton\'s laws. It was therefore predicted that another more distant planet must be perturbing Uranus orbit. Neptune was first observed by Galle and d\'Arrest on 1846 Sept 23 very near to the locations independently predicted by Adams and Le Verrier from calculations based on the observed positions of Jupiter, Saturn and Uranus. An international dispute arose between the English and French (though not, apparently between Adams and Le Verrier personally) over priority and the right to name the new planet; they are now jointly credited with Neptune\'s discovery. Subsequent observations have shown that the orbits calculated by Adams and Le Verrier diverge from Neptune\'s actual orbit fairly quickly. Had the search for the planet taken place a few years earlier or later it would not have been found anywhere near the predicted location.\n\n

More than two centuries earlier, in 1613, Galileo observed Neptune when it happened to be very near Jupiter, but he thought it was just a star. On two successive nights he actually noticed that it moved slightly with respect to another nearby star. But on the subsequent nights it was out of his field of view. Had he seen it on the previous few nights Neptune\'s motion would have been obvious to him. But, alas, cloudy skies prevented observations on those few critical days.</string>
    <string name="asia_info">Area : 43,820,000 \n
        Population :  4,164,252,000 \n
        Most Populous city : Shanghai, China</string>
    <string name="asia">The boundaries of Asia are not very clearly defined. There is actually no geographical separation as such between Asia and Europe. The two continents form a large landmass which is popularly called Eurasia. On the east of Asia you have the Pacific Ocean, Indian Ocean to the south and Arctic Ocean to the north. The continent is known for its vast diversity in terms of culture, environments, ethnic groups, economics, historical background, and also the government systems.</string>
    <string name="africa_info">Area : 30,370,000\n
        Population : 1,022,234,000\n
        Most Populous city : Lagos, Nigeria </string>
    <string name="africa"> Africa is the second largest continent in the world. It is also the second largest continent in the world in terms of population. Africa is commonly referred to as the black continent by many. This large land mass comprises of 54 countries and is home to one billion people. About 15 percent of the world population lives in this continent, which constitutes about 20 percent of the total land area. Africa lies in the centre of the earth with the equator passing through its centre. It is the only continent that stretches from the northern temperate to the southern temperate zones. The climate of Africa is largely tropical in nature. The northern and southern parts of Africa have temperate climatic conditions. Africa is also considered to be the birth place of mankind. The oldest fossils of Homo sapiens found till now have been from the eastern parts of this continent. This large and diverse continent is home to lot of endangered species. </string>
    <string name="antarctica_info">Area : 13,720,000\n
        Population : 4,490\n
        Most Populous city : McMurdo Station, US</string>
    <string name="antarctica"> Antarctica is the southernmost continent of all. The geographic south pole of the earth is contained in this continent. It is made of large permanent glaciers that surround the South Pole. This is one of the most uninhabitable places on earth. With a very small population of less than 5000 residents, Antarctica is the least populated continent on earth. It is also home to very few plant and animal species. Antarctica is also the coldest landmass on earth and much of this continent is made of permanent glaciers. Around 98% of the continent is covered by ice of about 1.9 kilometres thick. </string>
    <string name="australia_info">Area : 3,478,200\n
        Population : 29,127,000\n
        Most Populous city : Sydney, Australia</string>
    <string name="australia"> The continent of Australia is a single country continent. It is the sixth largest country by total area, and is also the smallest of all the seven continents. Because of its size, and isolated location, it is also called as island continent. Covering an area of 7617930 square kilometres, Australia lies in the Indo- Australian Plate. This continent is surrounded by Indian Ocean and Pacific Ocean. Australia is one of the least populated continents and is rich in biodiversity. The Great Barrier Reef, which is the largest coral reef in the world, is in Australia. It extends over 2000 kilometres in the north east cost of Australia. Australia is also home to world’s largest monolith, Mount Augustus. </string>
    <string name="europe_info">Area : 3,930,000\n
        Population : 738,199,000\n
        Most Populous city : Moscow, Russia</string>
    <string name="europe"> Europe is the second smallest continent in the world. It comprises the westernmost peninsula of the giant Eurasian landmass. Covering almost 2 percent of the earth’s surface Europe takes 6.8 percent of the world’s total land area. Europe is home to almost 50 countries and is the third most populated continent in the world after Asia and Africa. About 11 percent of the world’s population lives in Australia. Russia is the largest country in Europe and Vatican City is the smallest. Russia has got territory in both the continents of Europe and Asia, and it takes up around 40% of the land area of Europe </string>
    <string name="north_info">Area : 9,460,000\n
        Population : 542,056,000\n
        Most Populous city : Mexico City, Mexico</string>
    <string name="north">North America is a continent which lies wholly in the northern hemisphere. It is bordered by Arctic Ocean in the north, Atlantic Ocean in the east, Pacific Ocean in the south and west, and South America and Caribbean Sea in the south east. North America lies almost wholly in the western hemisphere. North America covers almost 4.8 percent of the earth’s surface and comprises around 16.5 percent of the whole land area on earth. North America is home to nearly 565 million people. About 7.5 percent of the world’s population lives here. It is the third largest continent in the world by area and fourth largest continent by population. Most of the land and area of the continent is dominated by Canada, United States of America, Greenland and Mexico. There are also many smaller states in the Central America and Caribbean regions.  </string>
    <string name="south_info">Area : 6,890,000\n
        Population : 392,555,000\n
        Most Populous city : São Paulo, Brazil</string>
    <string name="south">South America is a continent located in the western hemisphere with most of its land area lying in the southern hemisphere and a relatively small portion in the northern hemisphere. It has Pacific Ocean to its western side, Atlantic Ocean in the north and eastern side, and North America and Caribbean Sea in the North West side. With an area covering 17,840,000 square kilometres and a population of more than 3 billion, South America is the fourth largest continent in terms of size and fifth in terms of population. South America is home to twelve sovereign states and two non sovereign states. It is generally considered to be a subcontinent of the Americas.  </string>
    <string name="us_info">Population : 313,232,044 \n
                    Area : 3,718,691</string>
    <string name="us">This country has serious issues. A too large and corrupt government, too powerful corporatism, fake politicians, horribly fragile economy, corrupt justice system, crappy education system, clowns in office for the past 25 years, etc. I could literally go on forever about how screwed we the people are. But despite all of that, I still put USA at the top because of where we came from. We had wonderful founding fathers who hate tyranny and love liberty, yet they are demonized today. These great men forged the greatest piece of writing ever created in this country called The Constitution of the United States of America. This is what makes the USA great. This is why we have had such glorious freedom for so long now. This Constitution has outdone every other constitution in existence and its principles can even help us in the mess we are in today. But our leaders are violating it every day without a care and without punishment. </string>
    <string name="india_info">Population : 1,189,172,906 \n
                    Area : 1,269,338</string>
    <string name="india">I love my country very much because there are different languages, peoples unity so like my country very much

Yes, India is the most pluralistic country in the world whether it is religious or linguistic. India has public holidays for all religious festivals. NO OTHER COUNTRY has holidays for minority religions, period. And the government doesn\'t control lives of its citizens like many "developed" countries do.</string>
    <string name="uk_info">Population : 62,698,362\n
                    Area : 94,525</string>
    <string name="uk"> First industrialized nation, created the modern world. The world speaks English. Common law, Magna Carta and the Bill of Rights are its wonderful legacy. The only major country in the top ten science Nobel Laureates per capita. With the Dutch, created the western free trade model. The most innovative people on the planet. Time itself is measured from the United Kingdom. Still a military superpower, the country remains uninvaded since 1066, longer than any other nation. Its armed forces are the best-trained in the world. A huge cultural and historical wealth makes it one of the top 5 most-visited countries. London is one of the only two Alpha++ global cities. As a financial centre the UK remains ranked in either first or second place, its geographical location enabling in to trade effectively with the world as a whole. It is one of only two countries to have top-ten placed universities: it is a centre of learning.    </string>

    <string name="canada_info">Population : 34,030,589\n
                    Area : 3,855,081</string>
    <string name="canada">Canada may not have the largest population, nor the biggest army, and may not have the biggest economy. But what this Great North strong and free has is good people, good economy, amazing natural areas, and diverse culture. In Canada any man, woman, or child who immigrates may get dual citizenship allowing them to further express themselves in the our Great cultural mosaic. Better to be a vibrant individual of Canada, than be another bit of grey slop in the American melting pot. The Canadians conquered Vimy Ridge when no other could, we fought for the allies in WWII. Also, if American is "so good" then why do they always use Canadian cities to represent American cities in their "good" films? Also the Canadian Political system is superior to the American for the reason that if the Prime Minister says there is something that should be done, it is then done! None of the pointless banter between a congress and a president. </string>
    <string name="japan_info">Population : 126,475,664\n
                    Area : 145,882</string>
    <string name="japan">Japan is the best!
Japan is a very advanced country, great technology and perfect facilities. Japan is beautiful as a picture. The people here are very friendly, nice, trustful and helpful. I want to live there!</string>
    <string name="australia2_info">Population : 21,766,711\n
                    Area : 2,967,893</string>
    <string name="australia2">Australia would have to be a serious contender for the Best Country in the world - to live. It is the worlds largest Island, has enormous natural wealth (93% of what the world requires to survive can be found in Australia). Has a population of only 22 million in a country the size of main land US (excluding Alaska) surrounded by some of the very best pristine beaches on the planet. One of the only countries in the world that didn\'t enter into a recession during the GFC. Has a very small national debt which will be in the black with in 2 years. The most diverse melting pot of different nationalities on the planet (more than the US) and it\'s beautiful from the tropical heat in the North to the icy snow down south, Australia has it all. I\'ve lived in Europe, the US, Hong Kong and Singapore, traveled the world extensively and easily chose Australia to live permanently. \'It was a very easy choice.</string>

    <string name="germany_info">Population : 81,471,834\n
                    Area : 137,846</string>
    <string name="germany">I\'ve lived here, I\'ve lived in Italy and I\'ve lived in S Korea. I like them all better than the good old USA. I was born in the US and I don\'t think I will ever go back. They brag about freedom in the US but I have somthing here in Germany that you can never have in the US. The freedom to walk around at anytime, anywhere and not have to worry about getting robbed or shot. Plus the countryside is just down right gorgeous!</string>
    <string name="agra">Famous with one of the Seven Wonders of the World ,Taj Mahal, Agra is amongst the most prominent tourist destination in India. Agra is a virtual fortification of history and architecture. Historical landmarks, architectural grandeur ventures and the wonderfulness of marbles makes Agra as one of the vacationer objectives in India.</string>
    <string name="banglore">Bangalore renamed Bengaluru is the ,The Garden city of India gloats now of additionally being The Silicon Valley of India. A delightful city of Bangalore is perfectly brightened with parks, enclosures, lakes and wellsprings. It likewise serves as an impeccable stopover for some exceptionally wonderful spots close-by incorporating Mysore and the Jog Falls.</string>
    <string name="delhi">Delhi is the image of old and new India that’s essentialness lies not simply in its past glory as the seat of empires and grand landmarks, additionally in the rich and various cultures. Delhi offers lots of fascinating places and attractions to the guest, to such an extent that it comes to be challenging to choose from where to start exploring the city.</string>
    <string name="jaipur">Jaipur, lovingly alluded to as the Pink City in view of the pink dividers and the structures of the old city, baits guests with its staggering reminders of a past time. The most famous Jaipur attractions and places to visit are the aged royal residences and forts; with expanded construction modeling that serves as a brilliant indication of their royal heritage.</string>
    <string name="kolkata">Kolkata has a different and interesting history, which youll truly have the ability to submerge yourself in on one of these Kolkata strolls. Then again, there are likewise strolling tours in Calcutta that will give you an up to date look inside the city.</string>
    <string name="lucknow">Lucknow is a wonderful city that still holds its old planet appeal. Among the most vital monuments are the Imambadas, prominently regarded as the Bada Imambada and the Chhota Imambada. The trip spots additionally give one the thought of the districts rich flora and fauna.</string>
    <string name="mumbai">Mumbai is the largest city and also regarded as the business capital of India. Mumbai on the net is a tribute to Mumbais individuals, society history and quirks.  This city is full of life and is additionally known for its well known visitor’s places, beaches, Bollywood Movies, temples, etc.</string>

</resources>
